codewithchris.com 2019-08-16

# Privacy Policy and Affiliate Disclosure

### Introduction

As a reader of many other sites, I understand how important privacy, is especially in this day and age.

I want to ensure that my readers feel as safe as possible and the information below is full disclosure on what happens on CodeWithChris.com (a.k.a the Site).

Rest assured that I will **never share your information or email with anyone else.**

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. By visiting and using the Site, you agree that your use of the Site, and any dispute over privacy, is governed by this Privacy Policy. Because the Web is ever evolving, I may need to change our Privacy Policy at some point in the future, in which case I’ll post the changes to this Privacy Policy on the Site and update the Effective Date of the policy to reflect the date of the changes. By continuing to use the Site after I post any such changes, you accept the Privacy Policy as modified. If you have any questions or concerns regarding my privacy policy please use our contact form [here](https://codewithchris.com/contact/).

Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily make your personal information available for viewing by third parties online – for example on message boards, web logs, through email, or in chat areas – that information can be seen, collected and used by others besides me. I cannot be responsible for any unauthorized third-party use of such information.

### Log Files

Like many other websites, CodeWithChris.com uses log files to help learn about when, from where and how often traffic flows to this site. The information in the log files include:

Internet Protocol addresses (IP)  
Types of browser  
Internet Service Provider (ISP)  
Date and time stamp  
Referring and exit pages  
Number of clicks  
All of this information is not linked to anything that is personally identifiable.

### Cookies and web beacons

Like nearly all Websites, CodeWithChris.com stores “convenience” cookies on your computer whenever you leave a comment. These cookies record the name, and email address that you enter when you submit a comment so that you wont have to re-type that information the next time you leave a comment.

Third-party advertisers may also place and read cookies on your browser and/or use web beacons to collect information. CodeWithChris.com has no access or control over these cookies. You should review the respective privacy policies on any and all third-party ad servers for more information regarding their practices and how to opt-out.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your web browser options.

Instructions for doing so and for other cookie-related management can be found on the specific web browsers’ websites.

 **Amazon**

Amazon, a third party affiliate marketing network, uses cookies to help make sure I get a commission when you buy a product after clicking on a link or ad banner that takes you to the site of one of their merchants. You can read [Amazon’s Privacy Policy](http://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=468496).

 **Google Adsense**

Google Adsense, a third party advertising network, uses cookies to help make sure I get a commission when you buy a product after clicking on a link or ad banner that takes you to the site of one of their merchants. You can read [Google Adsense Privacy Policy](http://support.google.com/adsense/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=48182).

 **Google Analytics**

Google Analytics is a web analytics tool I use to help understand how visitors engage with this website. It reports website trends using cookies and web beacons without identifying individual visitors. You can read [Google Analytics Privacy Policy.](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html)

 **Google Site Stats**

To measure performance, Google uses small strings of text (known as cookies) that are placed on your computer when you click on ads. Cookies typically remain active on your computer for about 30 days. If you visit certain pages of the advertiser’s website during that period, Google and the advertiser will be able to tell that you saw the ad delivered by Google. You can read more about Google Site Stats [here.](https://services.google.com/sitestats/en_US.html?cid=1060759437)

 **Google Remarketing**

We use Google AdWords Remarketing to advertise CodeWithChris across the internet, in particular on the Google Display Network.

AdWords remarketing will display ads to you based on what parts of the CodeWithChris website you have viewed by placing a cookie on your web browser.

This cookie does not in any way identify you or give access to your computer or mobile device.

The cookie is used to indicate to other websites that “This person visited a particular page, so show them ads relating to that page.”

Google AdWords Remarketing allows us to tailor our marketing to better suit your needs and only display ads that are relevant to you.

If you do not wish to see ads from CodeWithChris you can opt out in several ways:  
1\. Opt out of Google’s use of cookies by visiting Google’s [Ads Settings](http://www.google.com/settings/ads).  
2\. Opt out of a third-party vendor’s use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

### How Do We Store Your Information?

Your information is stored on a list server (i.e. Drip) that delivers my content and messaging. Your information can only be accessed by those who help manage those lists to deliver e-mail to those who agree to receive my material.

All of the messaging or emails that are sent to you by me include an unsubscribe link in them. You can remove yourself at any time from the mailing list by clicking on the unsubscribe link that can be found in every communication that I send you.

### Email Subscriptions

Users may choose to receive email updates via Drip by submitting an email address to the email subscription form. I use a secure opt-in subscription system and I reserve the right to contact subscribers with information related to this website and blog. Subscribers may unsubscribe anytime and every email delivered will contain an “Unsubscribe” link.

When leaving a comment, users must submit a name and email address. To combat spam, the Disqus commenting platform also records the IP address of anyone submitting a comment.  
Again, none of this information will be shared with anyone.

### Removing Your Data

If you would like to be removed from the email newsletter, you can click the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of any of my emails or you can simply use the contact form [here](https://codewithchris.com/contact/) to ask me to remove you.

To remove your Disqus comments from my site, you must do that yourself by logging into your Disqus account at [Disqus](https://disqus.com/) and managing your comments.

### Facebook

As an advertiser on Facebook and through my Facebook page, CodeWithChris may collect content or information from a Facebook user. Such information may be used in the same manner specified in this Privacy Policy. You consent to the collection of such information. CodeWithChris abides by Facebook’s Data Use Restrictions.

  * Any ad data collected, received or derived from our Facebook ad (“Facebook advertising data”) is only shared with someone acting on my behalf, such as a service provider. I’m responsible for ensuring that my service providers protect any Facebook advertising data or any other information obtained from me, limit the use of all of that information, and keep it confidential and secure.
  * I do not use Facebook advertising data for any purpose (including retargeting, commingling data across multiple advertisers’ campaigns, or allowing piggybacking or redirecting with tags), except on an aggregate and anonymous basis (unless authorized by Facebook) and only to assess the performance and effectiveness of my Facebook advertising campaigns.
  * I do not use Facebook advertising data, including the targeting criteria for a Facebook ad, to build, append to, edit, influence, or augment user profiles, including profiles associated with any mobile device identifier or other unique identifiers that identify any particular user, browser, computer or device.
  * I do not transfer any Facebook advertising data (including anonymous, aggregate, or derived data) to any ad network, ad exchange, data broker or other advertising or monetization related service.

### General Data Privacy Regulation (GDPR)

The GDPR takes effect on May 25, 2018, and is intended to protect the data of European Union (EU) citizens. CodeWithChris markets its site, content, products and/or services online but I do not specifically target marketing to the EU or conduct business in or to the EU in any meaningful way. If the data that you provide to me in the course of your use of the Site, content, products and/or services is governed by GDPR, CodeWithChris will abide by the relevant portions of the Regulation.

If you are a resident of the European Economic Area (EEA) or are accessing this site from within the EEA, you may have the right to request: access to, correction of, deletion of; portability of; and restriction or objection to processing, of your personal data. This includes the “right to be forgotten.”

To make any of these requests, please get in touch with using our contact form [here](https://codewithchris.com/contact/).

### Affiliate Disclosure

“CodeWithChris.com is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to amazon.com, amazonsupply.com, or myhabit.com.”

Unfortunately, that’s some jargon that I had to include in my policy, but let me speak in plain English from here on:

Currently I’m an affiliate with Amazon and a publisher in the Google Adsense program so you may see some of the advertisements on the site and some of the links in my articles or on the Resources page are affiliate links which means that I’ll collect a small percentage of the sale as commission.

The reason that these are in place is because the small commissions add up and help support the costs to run the site and helps me feed my family without being overly intrusive to my audience’s experience and learning on the site.

These commissions will never come at a cost to yourself and I vow that whether a particular product offers a commission or not, it will never influence my recommendations or teaching material. I know that trust takes a lifetime to build but only seconds to lose, so you can rest assured that I only link to products which I have used personally and would recommend, as a teacher, to my audience for the purpose of learning, building or marketing iOS apps.

With that said, I’d like to sincerely thank you and my readers.

Chris

 **Last Updated: June 1st, 2018**
